Excuse me.Could you tell me how to get to the medical school?
请问 医学院怎么走?
I'm supposed to be doing a lecture in 20 minutes, and my driver's a bit lost.
我二十分钟后有个演讲 但是我的司机迷路了
You go straight ahead and you make a left over the bridge.
从这儿直走 过了桥然后左转
That's a lovely accent you have.
你的口音好可爱哦
New Jersey?
新泽西人?
Austria.
奥地利
Austria?
奥地利呀?
well, then...
好吧 那就......
good day, mate.
天气不错呀
Let's put another shrimp on the barbie.
咱们去烧烤吧!
Let's not.
去你的
who's got the wiener schnitzel?
谁要燻烤牛肉香肠?
Beautiful. There you go, Dolf.
好狗狗 多夫 就给你
There you go, buddy. Yeah, enjoy.
拿去 小家伙 慢慢吃
Let's see, next we got roast beef au jus.
我看看 接下来 我们还有烧烤酱汁牛肉
who's got the roast beef au jus?
谁要烧烤酱汁牛肉?
Stella, beautiful. Bon appetit, Stella.
史黛拉 漂亮! 好好享用啊!
Yeah, walk away. Go on, go on.
走开 去! 去!
Last but not least, footlong.
最后一个是巨无霸!
who's got the footlong?
谁要巨无霸?
Very...Very funny, Rascal.
真...真可笑 淘气鬼
Very funny. In your dreams.
凭你? 做梦去吧
Harry, why haven't you dropped those dogs off at the show yet?
哈利 那些要演出的狗怎么还没送到?
Sir, I didn't want to send them to a performance on an empty stomach, sir.
这个......我不希望看到他们饿着肚子表演
Get a move on it.
废话少说快点送来
Yes, sir. Mutt Cutts. Ten-four.
好的 先生 我马上到
Suck me sideways.
妈妈咪呀
Hello.How are you?
你好
I'll be out in one minute. Okay.
我马上就出来 好的
why you going to the airport?
你为什么要去机场?
Flying somewhere?
搭飞机去哪里?
How'd you guess? well, I saw your luggage.
你怎么知道? 我看到你的行李箱
Then when I noticed the airline ticket, I put two and two together.
又看到机票 然后就猜出来了
So where you headed? Aspen.
那么你要去哪? 亚斯本
Mm. California. Beautiful.
加利福尼亚呀 好地方
Name's Christmas, Lloyd Christmas.
我叫克里斯穆斯 劳埃德·克里斯穆斯
I'm Mary Swanson.
我叫玛丽·斯文森
This isn't my real job, you know.
这不是我的正式工作 你知道吗
No? Nope.
不是? 不是!
My friend Harry and I are saving up our money to open our own pet store.
我和我朋友哈利正努力赚钱 想开宠物店
That's nice.
那真不错
I Got worms.
我有虫
I beg your pardon? That's what we're gonna call it.
你说什么? 店名打算叫 "我有虫"
I Got worms. we're gonna specialize in selling worm farms.
我有虫 专门贩卖虫子
You know, like ant farms?
就像那些专卖蚂蚁的?
what's the matter?
怎么了?
A little tense about the flight?
坐飞机会紧张?
Something like that.
差不多吧
There's really nothing to worry about.
没什么好担心的 玛丽
Statistically, you're more likely to get killed on the way to the airport.
据统计 在你去机场路上遇上交通事故的机率 较大
Like in a head-on crash or flying off a cliff or getting trapped under a gas truck.
比如说撞车啊 冲出悬崖啦 或是被压在卡车底下
That's the worst.
那真是最惨的
I have this cousin...well, I had this cousin. He's like, pbbt...
我有个表兄弟......曾经有过一个表兄 他有点......
Lloyd, could you keep your eyes on the road, please?
劳埃德 你开车时能不能往前看?
Oh, yeah.
当然
Good thinking.
好建议
Can't be too careful.
小心驶得万年船
Lot of bad drivers out there.
这里的人开车跟疯子一样
Hey, watch it!
当心!
Okay, gang. You know the rules.
好了 伙计们 你们知道规矩啦
No humping, no pushing, no sniffing heinies.
不准乱跑 不准乱推 不准乱嗅
where have you been?
你去哪了?
My dogs were supposed to be here 40 minutes ago.
我的狗40分钟前就该到了
Now, I hardly have any time to primp them.
现在我几乎没时间打扮它们了
Don't worry about a thing, Mrs. Neugyburger.
别担心 纽西柏格太太
Neugeboren. Neu...Neu...Neu...
纽西柏恩 纽西...纽西...纽西
Boren. Boren. These pooches...
柏恩 柏恩 这些狗...
are not gonna need primping. You know why? Because I ...
压根不用打扮 您知道为啥不? 因为我......
bathed them and I clipped them myself.
亲自给它们洗澡 和剪毛
And I stand by my performance.
我做事您放心
On second thought, you might wanna run a comb through them.
现在我建议 您稍稍给它们梳理一下
The white zone is for...
白色区域仅供......
the immediate loading and unloading of passengers only.
旅客出入通用道
No parking.
请勿停车
Thanks. Here you go. Oh, no, Mary.
谢谢 这给你 别 玛丽
I couldn't possibly accept that.
我不能接受这个
Not after all we've been through.
在我们经过这么漫长的旅程之后
Thank you, Lloyd.
谢谢你 劳埃德
Good luck with your worms. Thanks.
祝你和你的虫子好运 谢谢
How about a hug?
来个临别拥抱?
The white zone is for the immediate loading and unloading of passengers only.
白色区域仅供旅客出入通用道
No parking.
不准停车
I hate goodbyes.
我讨厌离别
Uh, Lloyd... Shh.
劳埃德......  嘘
Just go.
就这么走吧
Be strong.
要坚强
Mr. Dan Richard, please pick up the white courtesy phone.
丹·理查德先生 请接机场免费电话
She's gonna leave the briefcase near the escalator.
她会在自动扶梯旁 放下手提箱
You make the pickup. Piece of cake.
你去拿 小事一桩
Goodbye, my love
再见 我的爱
Bye.
再见了
passenger warren passion, please pick up the white courtesy phone.
旅客莫拉·派森 请接机场免费电话
You have a message.
您有一个留言
passenger warren passion....
旅客莫拉·派森...
Mary!
玛丽!
There's our payday.
我们发财了
She left it. Let's go. Excuse me.
她放下了 我们走 抱歉
Coming through.
借过一下
Move it or lose it, sister.
小姐 让开! 快让开!
Hold that plane!
拦住那架飞机!
Sir, you can't go in there.
先生 你不能进去
It's okay.
不要紧
I'm a limo driver.
我是豪华房车司机哦
Hi, Lloyd. Hi, Harry.
劳埃德 哈利
How was your day?
今天过得怎样?
Not bad. Fell off the Jetway again.
不算坏 只是又从登机道摔下了
who the hell do you figure this guy's working for, anyway?
他奶奶的到底在替谁工作?
I don't know...
不知道......
but we sure as hell better find out.
我们必须查出来
The ulcer? I'll live.
溃疡? 死不了
So you got fired again, huh? Oh, yeah.
然后你就这样又被炒了? 是啊
They always freak out when you leave the scene of an accident, you know?
当你离开事故现场后 他们总是一团糟
Yeah, well, I lost my job too.
真巧 我也失业了
Man, you are one pathetic loser.
兄弟 你真是个可怜的输家
No offense. No. None taken.
没有恶意 没事 我不介意
You know what really chaffs my ass, though?
你知道真正让我不爽的是什么吗?
I spent my life savings turning my van into a dog.
我花光所有的积蓄 把我的货车装饰成一只蠢狗的模样
Hi, Petey.
皮弟!
The alarm alone cost me 200. Hey, chicks love it.
光警报器就花了200 小妞们喜欢呀
It's a shagging wagon.
毛茸茸的多可爱啊
what's with the briefcase?
那个手提箱哪来的?
It's a love memento.
这是世界上最美丽的女人
The most beautiful woman alive.
留给我的爱的纪念品
I drove her to the airport, sparks flew, emotions ran high.
我开车送她去机场 一路上火花迸射 气氛浓郁
She actually talked to me, man.
她和我聊天来着
Get out of here. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
不可能 真的
Tractor beam.
我俩就这样情不自禁地
Sucked me right in.
坠入爱河了
Anyway...
不过呢......
she left this in the terminal and flew to Aspen and out of my life.
她留下了这个 走人了 离开我去亚斯本了
what's in it?
里面是什么?
Man, I would have to be a lowlife...
拜托 我岂是一个......
to go rooting around in somebody else's private property.
随便乱翻别人隐私的人
ls it locked?
锁住了吗?
Yeah, really well.
嗯 可牢着呢
There's two of them. One of them's got a gun.
有两个人 其中一个有枪
Did you pay the gas bill?
你交瓦斯费了吗?
Hey... -Do you realize what you've done?
喂 你知道你干了什么好事吗?
I'm sorry. I say we bail.
对不起 我们还是快闪吧
Okay.
好
Briefcase ain't here. He must have taken it with him.
手提箱不在这 肯定被他们带走了
well, he's gotta come home sometime.
反正他一定还要回来的
Maybe we should trash the place, send him a little message.
干脆把这里砸个稀巴烂 给他点教训
I don't think he's gonna get that message, Joe.
我看砸了也和现在差不多烂
I mean, the guy's got worms in his living room.
这些家伙居然在客厅里养虫
Yeah.
没错
Oh, I got a better idea.
我有一个更好的主意
I thought I saw a pussy cat.
我想我看见一只小猫了
Oh, I did. I did. Come here.
真的 到这儿来
I can't believe we drove around all day and there's not a single job in this town.
真不敢相信我们开了一整天的车 却找不到一份工作
There is nothing, nada, zip.
什么都没有! 无! 零!
Yeah, unless you wanna work 40 hours a week.
是啊 除非你想一周工作40个小时
Pbbt.  Here.
他奶奶的 帮我拿一下
I'm gonna go to the store.
我要去买点东西
Okay, just get the bare essentials. That's the last of our dough.
钱要花在刀口上 咱可剩没几个钱了
Hey, what do I look like?
拜托 我长得像凯子吗?
Cripes.
我靠
Excuse me, little old lady.
打扰一下 老太太
Do you have change of a dollar? Change? No, I'm sorry, I don't.
你有一块钱零钱吗? 零钱? 抱歉 没有
well, could you do me a favor and watch my stuff here...
那么 能帮我看着这些东西吗......
while I go break a dollar?
然后我去换零钱?
Of course. Thanks.
当然可以 谢谢
I guess they're right.
看来大家说的没错
Senior citizens, although slow and dangerous behind the wheel...
老太婆虽然笨手笨脚 开车爱横冲直撞......
can still serve a purpose.
但也并非一点用处都没有
I'll be right back. Don't you go dying on me.
我马上回来 别死这哦
where's the booze?
酒呢?
I got robbed by a sweet old lady on a motorized cart.
我被一个坐轮椅的可爱老太太抢劫了
I didn't even see it coming.
打死我也想不到啊
Harry. No.
哈利? 不
Come on, Harry.
别这样 哈利
Cheer up. It gets worse, Lloyd.
开心点 还有更惨的事呢 劳埃德
My parakeet, Petey?
我的鹦鹉皮弟
Yeah?
怎么了?
He's dead.
它死了
Oh, man. I'm sorry, Harry.
不会吧 真是伤心
what happened?
怎么死的?
His head fell off.
它的脑袋掉了
His head fell off?
脑袋掉了?
Yeah, he was pretty old.
是啊 它已经一把年纪了
That's it.
够了
I've had it with this dump!
我受够这鬼地方了!
we got no food, we got no jobs...
我们没吃的 没工作......
our pets, heads are falling off!
我们鹦鹉的头还掉了!
Okay, just calm down. what the hell are we doing here, Harry?
冷静 我们还待在这鬼地方干啥?
we gotta get out of this town.
我们应该离开这个镇
Yeah, and go where? where are we gonna go?
然后呢 去哪? 我们到哪去啊?
I'll tell you where.
我告诉你去哪
Someplace warm.
一个温暖的地方
A place where the beer flows like wine.
那里的啤酒像葡萄酒一样
where beautiful women instinctively flock like the salmon of Capistrano.
漂亮女人就像卡匹斯佐诺的大马哈鱼一样聚集
I'm talking about a little place called Aspen.
我是在说一个小地方叫 亚斯本
I don't know, Lloyd. The French are assholes.
劳埃德 我不确定耶 法国人都是混球
wait a minute.
等等
wait a minute. I know what you're up to, mister.
等等 我知道你想干什么了 兄弟
Yeah, you just wanna go to Aspen and find that girl who lost her briefcase...
你是想去亚斯本 找那个丢了手提箱的漂亮小妞...
and you need me to drive you there, right?
而且你需要我当你的司机 对吧?
Am I right? Am I right? Am I right, Lloyd? Yeah. So? Yeah. So?
我说对了吧? 劳埃德? 是啊 那又怎样?
So I wanna go someplace where we know somebody...
我就是想去一个......
who can plug us into the social pipeline.
能让我们出人头地的地方
No. No, no, no, Lloyd.
不 不 不 不 劳埃德
No. I say we stay here, we hunt for jobs and we keep saving our money...
不要 我们还是待在这里 找份工作赚钱......
for the worm store.
开家虫子店
I don't know about you, but I am getting sick and tired...
我不知道你怎么想的 可是我已经受够了......
of running from creditors.
天天躲债的日子
You know what I'm sick and tired of, Harry?
哈利 你知道我受不了什么吗?
I'm sick and tired of having to eke my way through life.
我讨厌自己夹着尾巴做人
I'm sick and tired of being a nobody.
我恨自己只是个无名小卒
But most of all...
但最令我沮丧的是......
I'm sick and tired of having nobody.
我没有爱人
Okay, Lloyd.
好吧 劳埃德
Aspen it is.
咱们就去亚斯本
You'd better not be fooling.
你没开玩笑吧
Okay, okay.
没事的 没事的
Just let it out. Have a good cry. Come on.
狠狠痛哭一场吧 哭吧
Okay.
没事了
Okay, that's enough.
好了 够了
Lloyd, what are you doing?
劳埃德 你在干吗?
It feels like you're running at an incredible rate, Harry.
我觉得自己可以跑得超快 哈利
Quit it. we're not through Connecticut...
停下! 我们还没穿越康奈迪克州...
and already you're annoying me. I'm sorry.
你已经开始惹我厌了 抱歉
we're really doing it, though, aren't we, buddy?
老兄 我们真的来了 不是吗?
Hey, where did you get those?
你上哪搞来这些?
I bought them when we filled up.
加油时我买的
But wait, but you...we're supposed to talk about all expenditures, Lloyd.
我们应该好好讨论一下花费问题
we are on a very tight budget.
我们的预算很紧张的
This didn't come out of our travel fund.
这不是用旅行基金买的
No, I was able to raise 25 extra bucks before we left.
在我们出发前 我搞到了25块钱
where did you get 25 extra bucks?
你从哪搞来25块钱?
I sold some stuff to Billy in 4C.
我卖了些东西 给住在4C的比利
the blind kid? Yeah.
那个失明的孩子?  是的
Yeah.
是的
what did you sell him, Lloyd?
劳埃德 你卖了什么给他?
Stuff.
一些小玩意
what kind of stuff?
什么小玩意?
I don't know.
我记不清了
A few baseball cards, a sack of marbles...
一些棒球卡 一袋弹珠...
Petey.
皮弟
Petey?
皮弟?
You sold my dead bird to a blind kid?
你把我的死鸟卖给一个失明的小孩子?
Lloyd, the...That...You...what are you...?
劳埃德 你......你......你干了什么......?
Petey didn't even have a head.
皮弟甚至没有头了
Harry...
哈利......
I took care of it.
我都搞定了
Pretty bird.
漂亮的小鸟
Yeah, can you say "pretty bird"?
你能说 "漂亮的小鸟"吗?
Yes, pretty bird.
你是一只漂亮的小鸟
Pretty bird.
漂亮的小鸟
Polly want a cracker?
波利要不要吃饼干?
Those rat bastards. They're rubbing it right in our faces.
那群王八蛋 就这样眼睁睁的抢我们的东西
Man, Andre'll have a goddamn hemorrhage if we don't get that briefcase back.
要是不把那箱子拿回来 安德烈先生会发怒的
They must have been following us for weeks.
他们一定跟踪我们几星期了
why you say?
何出此言?
"Gas Man."
气体男人
How the hell do they know that I got gas?
他们怎么知道我有胃气?
They gotta be pros.
看来是专业的
Don't worry.
别担心
we're gonna get that money back.
我们会把钱拿回来的
And I'll tell you something else.
我来告诉你一些其他的
They ain't never getting to Aspen.
他们从来没有去过亚斯本
I'm gonna see to that.
我会牢牢盯着 走着瞧好了
They got the Monkees. They were a major influence on the Beatles.
顽童合唱团是受了披头士的影响
Yeah, I know.
没错 这我清楚
Excuse me, Flo?
等一下 跑腿的
Flo, like the TV show.
跑腿的 就像电视上说的
what is the soup du jour?
什么是"soup du jour"?
It's the soup of the day.
是今日的特色汤
Mm. That sounds good. I'll have that.
听起来真不错 我要一份
Anything else before I leave the area?
还要些别的吗?
No. Yep, yes.
不 要的 需要
Yes, my soda's flat. It doesn't have any bubbles.
需要 我的苏打水没气了 它都没泡泡了
Happy now?
开心了没?
Feels good to mingle with these laid-back country folk, don't it, Har?
拿这些乡巴佬寻开心真好玩 对吧 哈利?
I like it a lot.
干这种事超爽的
what? what's the matter?
咋啦 又咋了?
You spilled the salt. That's what's the matter.
你把盐弄撒了 就是这回事
Spilling the salt is very bad luck.
撒了盐是会带来晦气的
we're driving across the country. The last thing we need is bad luck.
我们要开车经过许多地方 最不需要的就是霉运
Quick, toss some salt over your right shoulder.
快点 从你的右肩上 扔些盐过去
what the hell?
什么?
Too little too late, Harry.
不过太迟了 哈利
who's the dead man that hit me with the salt shaker?
哪个死贱人敢用盐瓶扔我?
well, oh, that...It was a terrible mistake, sir.
这个...这真是个天大的误会 先生
Please, believe me. I would never do anything to offend a man of your size.
相信我 我从不敢冒犯像您这么大块头的人
Kick his ass, Sea Bass.
给他点颜色瞧瞧 黑鲈鱼
Go ahead, Sea Bass. You gonna eat that?
- 上啊 黑鲈鱼 - 你要吃那个?
what, that? No. Yes. No.
什么 这个? 不吃 吃 不吃
well, no. It crossed my mind. Yeah.
不吃 确定不吃 真的
Still want it?
还想吃吗?
No, you go ahead.
不 你请用吧
You really wimped out, man.
兄弟 你刚才真孬
what are you talking about, "wimped out"?
你说什么呀 孬?
what, what, did you s...?
干嘛 你没有看到...?
The guy hocked on my burger. what...? No, no, wait a second.
那个人在我的饼上吐痰......  等等
I think I just...
我刚刚......
I just had an idea.
想到个妙计
Follow me.
跟我来
Excuse me, guys.
各位 打扰一下
what the hell do you want?
你们他妈的想干嘛?
I just want to apologize for that unpleasant scene a little earlier.
我只是想为刚才的不愉快道歉
My friend Harry and I would...
我的朋友哈利和我......
like to buy you guys...
想请诸位......
a round of beers...
喝一打啤酒......
just to bury the hatchet.
让我们和解
Make it four boilermakers.
我们四个人要畅饮
whatever you want, sir.
你说怎样都行 老大
I'll have the waitress bring it over immediately.
我叫服务生立马拿过来
Lloyd, what are you doing? Shh.
劳埃德 你发什么疯? 嘘
we can't afford to buy them drinks. Shh.
我们根本没钱请他们喝酒! 嘘
Excuse me.
打扰一下
Sea Bass and the fellas offered to pick up our check.
黑鲈鱼和他的伙伴们 说要帮我们付帐
They said just put it on their tab.
他说记在他们的账上就行了
They're very nice.
他们人真好
Sea Bass said that?
黑鲈鱼这样说了?
well, if that guy at the table over there is Sea Bass....
如果坐在那张桌子的人叫黑鲈鱼的话......
All right, if that's what he wants.
好吧 如果他想这样
Put these on there too, okay? You got it.
把这些也记上 好吗?  拿走吧
Son of a...! I'm gonna kill those sons of bitches!
狗娘养......!  我要宰了那些狗娘养的!
That was genius, Lloyd. Sheer genius.
劳埃德 你太有才了! 真是十足的天才!
where did you come up with a scam like that?
你怎么想出这些鬼主意来?
Saw it in a movie once .
我从电影里看到的
That was incredible.
太难以置信了
what happened? Guy tricks some sucker...
电影后来怎样了? 一帮蠢货...
into picking up his tab and gets away scot-free?
替他付账 让他白吃白喝跑了?
No. In the movie...
不是 在电影里...
they catch up to him half mile down the road and slit his throat.
他们追了半里路 然后追上了他 割了他的喉咙
It was a good one.
真是部好电影
Harry? what?
哈利? 干嘛?
I know this isn't the best time, but when you get a chance to pull over...
我知道这不是好时机 但是你能不能开到路边......
Yeah? I gotta pee.
干嘛? 我要尿尿
what, are you crazy? I'm not pulling over now.
什么 发什么疯? 现在绝对不行
But I gotta go. what am I supposed to do? well....
- 可是我好急 怎么办? - 那......
whiz in one of the empty beer bottles. They're on the floor, just get one of...
后面有空酒瓶 尿在里面  在地板上 拿个来......
Quit playing around.
别撞过来啦!
what...? what...?
怎.....? 怎么......?
Shit.
妈的
watch the seat. Okay.
对准! 知道
watch the seat. All right.
要对准!  知道啦
what? what's wrong?
怎么了?
The bottle's almost full and I'm still going.
瓶子快满了 不过我还没尿完
So stop going. I'm still...
那就别尿了 我还在......
I can't stop going once I've started. It stings.
开始尿了 我就停不下来了 那是折磨
Quick, get me another bottle. what?
快 给我另外一只瓶子 什么?
Come on, hurry, hurry, hurry. Come on, come on.
快啦 快 快 快点快点
Here, here, here. Go. Okay.
好了 好了 拿着! 好了
Hold that.
拿着
Hold that one.
拿着这个
Hurry, I'm pitching it.
赶快呀 我正憋着
what are you, a camel?
你是什么 骆驼变的?
Pull over.
靠边停车
Huh? Pull over.
什么?  靠边停车!
No, it's a cardigan, but thanks for noticing.
我有穿羊毛衫 多谢提醒!
Yeah.
是啊
Killer boots, man.
不错的靴子 兄弟
Pull your vehicle to the side of the road.
把你的车子停在路边
License and registration, please.
请出示驾照
You fellas were going a little fast back there, wouldn't you say?
你们开得有点快啊 是不是?
You....
你......
You fellas been doing a bit of boozing, have you?
你们还喝了酒 是不是?
Sucking back on grandpa's old cough medicine?
长这么大还断不了奶啊?
No. Oh, no, sir. No. -No, no, no.
不 没喝酒 警察大人  没有没有
Yeah, well, what's that?
那些是什么?
That's nothing, sir. -Yeah, nothing.
没什么 大人 是啊 没什么的
well, are you aware that it's against the law...
你们知不知道 在宾夕法尼亚州......
to have an open alcohol container here in the state of Pennsylvania?
只要车里有开着的酒瓶就是犯法?
Come on. Give me that booze, you little pumpkin-pie-haircutted freak.
快点 把酒瓶给我 你这个南瓜头
Come on.
拿来
Sir, no, I... No, sir. Don't. Don't drink...
警官 不 别...... 警官 别 别喝......
You'd keep your mouth shut if you knew what was good for you, buddy.
识相的话 就乖乖把嘴给我闭上
Tic Tac, sir?
警官 怎么嘴抽筋呀?
Get the hell out of here.
给我他妈的滚蛋
How could they not have gotten the ransom?
他们怎么会没有拿到赎金?
It just doesn't make sense.
绝对不可能
I left the money exactly where they instructed me to.
我明明就把钱 放在约好的地方了啊
Oh, it makes perfect sense, Mary.
怎么不可能 玛丽
we should have called the authorities the minute we knew Bobby was kidnapped.
鲍比被绑架的时候我们本来就应该叫警察的
Helen, we've been through this already. Mr.Andre.
海伦 我们已经讨论过这个问题了 安德烈先生
Nicholas. Karl.
尼古拉斯 卡尔
Nick, Nick, Nick. Nick.
尼克 尼克 尼克 尼克
Any word yet, sir?
有消息了吗?
No. Nothing yet, Nicholas.
还没有 尼古拉斯
I've been giving this a lot of thought.
有件事我想了很久
Maybe we should cancel the preservation benefit.It'll be so easy to re-schedule.
也许我们该取消这周末的义演活动 下次再安排
I don't think we should do anything out of the ordinary.
不 我们不应该打乱原有的计划
It's imperative that we carry on as usual.
她说的对 现在最重要的就是一切维持正常
Okay. Especially you, Mary.
好吧 玛丽 尤其是你
what am I supposed to do? Go about my life like everything is fine?
那我应该怎么做? 当作什么事都没发生一样?
That's exactly what you should do. Yes. Go skiing. Go to parties.
没错 去滑雪 去聚会吧
Act normally, you know. Yeah, don't you see?
就像平时一样 你知道吗?
we can't let on that anything's wrong.
我们不能犯一点失误 千万不能让人看出来
If the press or the authorities get wind of this, the kidnappers may panic.
若让媒体知道这件事可能会引起绑匪恐慌的
I mean, you never know what they might do to him then.
你无法预测他们会对他 干出什么事来
So he said, "Do you love me?" And she says, "No...
然后他说 "你爱我吗? "她说 "不
but that's a real nice ski mask."
可是那滑雪面罩真好看"
Hey, man. what's that?
老兄 你看那是什么?
You want me to drive?
要换我来开吗?
No, I'm cool.
不用 我还行
Yes.
是
Yeah. You gonna get it.
是啊 你会得到的
Get her.
上她
Oh, yeah, bitch.
婊子
This is the life.
这才是人生
Cold beer, a hot tub and paper-thin walls.
冰啤酒 热泉浴 纸薄般的墙壁
There's only one thing that could make this moment any better.
现在只要再加上一件事 就真的是顶级的享受了
what's that?
什么事?
If you had a nice set of knockers.
如果你有一对完美的乳房
That's two things, Lloyd.
那是两个 劳埃德
Yeah, well, it's a good thing you're not stacked, Harry...
是啊 那是你从没尝试过的 哈利...
or I'll be banging you right now.
要不要我现在操你
I'd show you what a real man can do.
我会让你知道 什么才是一个真正的男人
Split you like an old piece of firewood.
撕裂你 让你求生不得 求死不能
You'd probably like it too, you big homo.
没准你会爱上这个 你这个死基佬
Shut up.
闭嘴
Don't tell me to shut up, woman.
别叫我闭嘴 小妞
Yes.
是
I don't know, Lloyd, this place doesn't really do it for me .
劳埃德 知道吗 这个地方真的不适合我
It brings back a lot of memories.
这地方让我想起许多往事
It was a few years ago.
那是几年前的事了
what happened, Harry?
怎么了 哈利?
Some little filly break your heart? No, it was a girl.
哪个小母马伤你的心了? 不是母马 是女孩
Fraida Felcher.
弗洛伊德·佛吉尔
we stayed in a place just like this. wasn't this classy, but you know, nice.
我们曾住过类似这样的地方 没这里好 但也很不错了
Felcher?
佛吉尔?
From Cranston?
克兰斯敦来的那个?
Yeah, you know her?
是啊 你认识她?
Oh, yeah.
当然
I mean, I remember you...
我是说我记得你......
talking about her.
曾经提过她
we had the most incredibly romantic time.
我们拥有过最浪漫的时光
I thought we were gonna be together forever, and then...
我以为我们会永远在一起......
About a week later, out of the blue she sends me a John Deere letter.
可是一个礼拜后 莫名奇妙地她寄给我一封绝情书
She give you any reason? Yeah, I called her up.
她有说为什么吗? 我给她打过电话
She gave me crap about me not listening to her enough or something.
她说什么我从来没认真听她说话之类的屁话
I don't know, I wasn't paying attention. But the thing that hurt the most is I think ...
我不清楚 也没仔细去听 但最令我伤心的是......
she was seeing another guy.
她心里有别人了
Never did find out who.
到现在还不知道是谁
Mr.Andre, guess who we just happened upon. Yeah. Yeah.
安德烈先生 知道我们刚才碰到谁了吗?
I had plans. I had things I wanted to do.
我有我的计划 做我想做的事
This is where it ends, in a phone booth.
这就是一切结束的地方 在一个电话亭
Yeah, the boys are holed up in a little love nest for the night.
是啊 那俩家伙还要在他们爱的小窝快活呢
I think they're a little bit strange.
我觉得他们有点怪怪的
what the hell are these guys up to? I mean...
他妈的他们到底是干什么的 我是说.....
is it possible they could be feds?
有没有可能是条子?
Highly unlikely from what I've seen.
我盯了这么久 不太像
Sir, did you ever hear of the concept of other people?
先生 你有没有听过 为别人着想这句话?
Me, being that, for the phone, sir...
我要用那个电话 先生...
You turned your back on me. Ooh, ooh!
你竟然还转头过去啊
He got me mad.I almost like it.
他快使我抓狂了
You were supposed to grab that bag so we could end this shit.
你们当时要是拿到箱子 我们今天就不用再搞这鸟事了
Here's your drink, baby.
亲爱的 你的酒
what I would... The damage I can do to you.
你知道我可以向你索赔精神损失吗?
Hold on a minute. Because you were spiteful. I didn't wanna...
等一下 因为你那是恶意的 我本不想...
That's not your problem. You didn't know.
那不是你在意的 你不鸟
Get off the phone.
从电话亭里滚出来
Get off the pho...
从电话亭里滚...
I'm sorry, Mr.Andre, you were saying?
抱歉 安德烈先生 您说什么来着?
Look, Mental, these jokers have got a lot of money and it belongs to me.
曼特尔 这帮孙子拿到了一堆钱 而这些钱是我的
I wanna know who they are. what they're doing with it.
我要马上知道他们是谁 拿我的钱在干嘛
I told you already I'm on it. All right?
我不是告诉过你 我正要去查吗
Good.
很好
According to the map, we've only gone about four inches.
根据这张地图指示 我们才走了四英寸
You know, I don't think we have enough gas money.
不过我想我们是不是快没汽油了
Relax. we have more than enough.
别紧张 还多着呢
I think you're wrong, Lloyd.
可是我觉得不够 劳埃德
How much you wanna bet?
来赌呀?
I don't bet.
我不打赌
what do you mean you don't bet? I don't bet.
说什么鬼话? 你不赌? 我不赌
I don't gamble. Pussy, pussy.
我说不赌就是不赌 胆小鬼 胆小鬼
I never have and I never will. Pussy.
我以前不赌 现在不赌 以后也不赌 胆小鬼
Yeah, right.
是吗 行
I bet I can get you gambling before the end of the day.
我就赌20元绝对会让你在今天以内打赌
No way.
想都别想
I'll give you 3-to-1 odds. No.
我让你一赔三?  不要
5-to-1 . No.
一赔五?  没门
10-to-1?
一赔十?
You're on.
成交
I'm gonna get you. Uh-uh.
我赢定了  不可能
I don't know how, but I'm gonna get you.
虽然我不知该怎么做 不过胜利肯定是属于我的
Come on, Joe. Let me do them. Let me do both of them.
拜托 让我去干掉他们 两个一起干掉
You don't have to worry about it. Just shut up.
你就什么都不用担心了  给我闭嘴
Now, we don't even know who the hell they are.
我们根本不知他们是何方神圣
You don't kill people you don't know. That's a rule.
不滥杀无辜 这是规矩
I want you to get up here, lie down on the front seat.
现在我要你马上过来 躺平在前座里
when they pick me up...
等我搭上他们的车......
you follow us. You got that?
你就在后头跟着 明白没?
Keep your shirt on. I gotta squeeze a lemon.
沉着点 别坏了大事啊
Hey, hey, hey. Here they come.
他们来了
Stay down. Stay down.
躲好 躲好
Say, are you guys going to Davenport?
你们两位有要去达文波特吗?
My car died and I'm late for a luncheon.
我的车坏了 而且我中午有个餐会也迟到了
we usually don't pick up hitchhikers...
通常 我们是不随便载人的......
but I'm gonna go with my instinct on this one.
不过这次我决定顺从天意
Saddle up, partner.
上来吧 伙伴
You're it.
你是猪
You're it. You're it, quitsies.
你才是 你是猪 句号
You're it. Quitsies. No anti-quitsies. No startsies.
句号的相反 你是猪 句号 相反无效
You can't do that. Can to.
不算  算
Can't. Stamped it. Can too. Double stamped it. No erasies.
不算 踩你  算 踩你踩你 消除无用
Cannot. Triple stamped it. No erasies. Touch blue, make it true.
不算 踩你踩你踩你 消除无用
You can't triple stamp a double stamp, Lloyd.
你不能踩三次 劳埃德
You can't triple stamp a double stamp. You...Lloyd.Lloyd.
你不能踩三次啦 劳埃德
Guys! Enough!
两位! 够了啦!
wanna hear the most annoying sound in the world?
你想不想听听 世界上最刺耳的噪音啊?
Guys! Guys! Guys!
够啦! 够啦! 够了啊!
Fellas...
小伙子们......
you think we could listen to the radio or something?
咱们能不能听听收音机什么的?
Radio?
收音机?
who needs a radio? Ready, Harry?
要那鬼东西作啥? 哈利 预备
Mockingbird, everybody have you heard? Mockingbird, everybody have you heard?
大家有无听说过仿声鸟 大家有无听说过仿声鸟
She's gonna buy me a mockingbird She's gonna buy me a mockingbird
她要买只仿声鸟给我 她要买只仿声鸟给我
And if that mockingbird don't sing And if that mockingbird don't sing
如果那只鸟不肯唱歌 如果那只鸟不肯唱歌
She's gonna buy me a diamond ring She's gonna buy me a diamond ring
她要买只钻戒给我 她要买只钻戒给我
And if that diamond ring don't shine And if that diamond...
如果那只钻戒不够耀眼 如果那只钻戒......
Lloyd, there's people who want a ride too.
劳埃德 快看! 那里有人想搭便车
Pick them up.
也带上他们吧!
You want an Atomic Pepper, Mr. Mentalino?
要不要来点超级无敌小辣椒啊 曼特里诺先生?
No.
不用了
You guys go ahead.
你们俩先吃吧
I'll do it if you will, Lloyd.
你吃我就吃 劳埃德
Okay. You go first.
行 你先请
No. Uh-uh. No. You go first.
不 不 不 你先
No, you go first. No, you go first. No, you go first.
你先啦! 你先啦!
You go. I always go first. Oh, yeah.
你先吃 每次都我先!
why don't you guys both stop acting like a couple of pussies...
你们俩就别再扭扭捏捏 像娘们似的......
and go at the same time, huh?
要吃就同时一起吃?
That sounds like a dare, Harry. It's a double dare.
听来似乎是种挑战 对吧? 哈利 是双重挑战
Yeah, okay. You're on.
来就来 谁怕谁
It's not so bad. well?
一点也不辣嘛! 就是
It's more tingly than hot. Yeah.
有点麻麻的而已 就是
Now, if you fellas would excuse me, I gotta use the phone.
若你俩不介意的话 我出去打个电话
Enjoy your meal, guys.
小兄弟们 慢慢享用你们的午餐
Here, Lloyd. This helps. Here.
劳埃德 拿着 这个能止辣 拿去
It works good.
它很有效的
Yeah, it's Mental.
是我 曼特尔
I'm just sitting down to a nice meal with our boys.
我正和那俩蠢蛋一块享受大餐呢
How nice for you. Don't forget that your bread plate is on the left.
好极了 吃饭时小心别噎着啊
Look, I can't have these guys running around Aspen.
我可不想让那两只鼠辈 在亚斯本到处乱窜
Don't worry. They ain't gonna be running around nowhere...
放心好了 等我在他们的饮料里加了灭鼠药......
after I dump a little rat poison in their Shirley Temple.
他们酒再也窜不到哪去了
Good, good.
我加 我再加
That's good. Here he comes. Here he comes.
已经够了啦 他回来了 他回来了
Feeling better, girls? Yes, much better. Thank you for asking.
感觉好点了吗 小姐们?  好多了 多谢关心
So why you going to Aspen? Vacation?
你们俩来亚斯本干嘛? 度假?
why don't you eat up and we'll tell you.
你先吃完我们就告诉你
It just doesn't seem like you packed much.
你们没带多少行李啊
All I saw was one bag and a briefcase.
我就只看见一个袋子 和一只手提箱
No, no, the briefcase isn't even ours. Some lady left it at the airport.
那个啊 那个手提箱不是我们的 是一位女士遗留在机场的
we're just bringing it back to her. How's your burger?
我们不过是把它物归原主 你的汉堡好吃吗?
You mean you don't even know her?
你是说你们根本不认识她?
Talk about being in the wrong place at the wrong time.
老天爷真是爱开玩笑
Are you okay, man? It was just a goof.
你没事吧 老家伙? 我们不过是开个玩笑罢了
My ulcer.
我的溃疡
Quick, quick, my pills.
快 我的药
Somebody should call an ambulance.
或许应该去叫救护车
Look, you get the pills. Don't worry, I know CPR.
听好 你去拿药  不用担心 我会CPR
I'll get the pills. Out with the bad air, in with the good.
我去找药来 坏运走 好运来
Out with the bad air...
坏运快滚开......
No.
不要
This is a lot easier if you just lay back.
你乖乖躺好 会轻松多的
Here, here.
药来了
Here. He's resisting me.
药来了 我遭受到严厉的反抗
Here. Here you go. Here you go. Here you go.
药给你 快吃 快吃吧
Pills. Okay. Here you go. There you go.
吃药 快吃 快吃
Pills are good. Pills are good. Drink them down. Drink them down.
药有益健康 吞下去 吞下去
There you go. There you go, big guy. That's better.
药到病就除 大块头 好多了吧 这就对了
You want some ketchup and mustard? That helped us.
你要不要也试试 番茄酱加芥末酱?
Yeah.
那很有效的
You son of a...bitch!
狗娘......养的!
Check, please.
小姐 买单
I can't believe it.
我真不敢相信
Life's a fragile thing, Har.
生命竟是如此脆弱 哈利
One minute you're chewing on a burger, the next minute you're dead meat.
前一秒还在嚼汉堡 下一秒就翘辫子了
But he blamed me.
可是他竟咒骂我来着
You heard him. Those were his last words.
你有听到吗 他死前说的话
Not if you count the gurgling sound.
人死前都是会胡言乱语的
You mean he was poisoned?
你是说有人对他下毒?
No doubt about it.
一点也没错
They found these next to the body.
我们在尸体旁边发现了这个
Sir. Yeah?
长官 怎样?
waitress says he came in with a couple of younger guys.
服务生说 他是和两个年轻小伙子一起来的
They called the ambulance and then they hit the road.
他们叫了救护车后就溜掉了
Any idea where they were going? we received a report.
知道他们去哪了吗? 刚刚收到消息
They were seen headed west on l-80 towards Colorado.
他们在80号公路上 往科罗拉多方向过去
Did you get a make on the vehicle?
知道是什么样的车吗?
Yes, sir.
知道 长官
They're driving an '84 ...
他们开着一辆1984年的......
sheepdog.
牧羊犬
Skis, huh?
去滑雪?
That's right. Great.
是啊 真好
They yours?
那是你的?
Uh-huh.
是啊
Both of them?
两个都是?
Yeah.
对
Cool.
佩服
Excuse me, but you...You're spraying everywhere.
抱歉 不过你的......你的汽油洒的到处都是
Oh, man, you gotta be shitting me.
我靠 怎么是你呀
If it ain't my old friend.
你可不是我的老炮友啊
You're right on time.
不过既然又正是这个时候
That's a lot of luggage for a little vacation.
小小的度假 行李会不会带太多了?
Oh, I'm moving to Aspen.
我是搬家到亚斯本
I've gotta get away from my boyfriend. He's such a klutz.
我要离我那男朋友远一点 他是个变态
Plus my astrologer told me that I really should stay away from accident-prone guys.
算命师曾经告诉我务必远离麻烦制造者 所以
well, you know, l...
这样啊 我......
Here, it's a little loose. You might wanna...
还你 它有点松了 你最好再......
Thank you. No, hey, no.Allow me.
谢谢你 等我一下
I've got a thing of thing...Here, got them right here. Right here.
我这里正好有......这个...... 就是这个
Thank you.
谢了
Sure. You know, I'm heading up to Aspen myself.
不客气 我也正好要去亚斯本
Maybe we could, you know, meet up, have some hot chocolate or something.
或许我们可以......哪天聚聚一起喝点热巧克力什么的
Sure, why not.
当然 没问题
You seem harmless.
你人看起来挺不错的
I'm gonna give you my number.
我给你我的电话号码
Let me find a pen though. Great.
我先找只笔来 太棒了
Let's see. I know I have one in here somewhere.
我找找 我记得就放在这附近来着
Look, just tell it to me. I got a really good memory.
你直接告诉我就好了 我的记性可是超好的
well, the number's 555... 555.
那好吧 号码是555...... 555
905...wait a minute, that's my old number.
905......等等 不对 那是我以前的号码
That is so weird how your mind goes blank...
很奇怪吧 有时候你想说的 和说出来的完全不一样.......
For God's sakes just give me the damn number!
别管那些杂七杂八 只要告诉我那个该死的号码!
Okay, look, you're gonna get pushy, forget about it.
那么 刚刚的话就当作没说过吧
Find a happy place.
你找错人了
Find a happy place. Find a happy place.
你找错人了 你找错人了
I'll show you a happy place.
我会让你知道 你就是我要找的人
Here's your happy place.
这里就是你的天堂
Go around now. Go around.
四处探探 老兄 四处探探
All right. Any sign of them? No, but we're expecting them shortly.
有他们的行迹了吗? 没有 不过我们很快就能逮住他们了
A motorist saw a pooch about 30 miles back headed this way.
有个骑士在30哩外看见 一只杂种狗朝这边过来
Look, I told you what happened, so just drop it.
该说的我都已经告诉你了 就他妈的别再提了
Yeah, okay. Sure thing, Lloyd. Sure thing.
行 当然 没问题 劳埃德
I promise not to mention another word...
我保证绝对不会再说一个字......
about being in a bathroom with a 6'4" trucker with his pants down.
关于你在厕所和一个六尺四的卡车司机一起搞的事
Hey, look, we're almost in Colorado.
我们快到科罗拉多了
what do you say we change seats? I've been driving for nine straight hours.
换你来开行不行? 我已经连开九小时了
I don't have the energy to start a new state.
没那精力再开下个州了
why should I do you any favors? I'll let you kiss me.
凭什么要我听你的?  我会让你亲我的
I swear I'm gonna...
我发誓 我会让你......
Take your...I'm gonna...Swear to God I'm gonna take...
我绝对......我对天发誓 我绝对要把你......
Oh, don't...Don't touch me.
别......碰......我!
I'm done, okay. Enough.
我继续开 满意没?
Hey, guys. Oh, Big Gulps, huh? All right.
老兄 重量杯的啊? 真能吃
well, see you later.
那么 回头见
Hey, Harry, I got some beef jerk...
哈利 我买了些牛肉干...
Some people just weren't cut out for life on the road.
有人啊 事先就是不会做时间规划
I was wondering when you were gonna get up.
我还在想你何时才会醒呢
well, how long have I been out?
我睡了多久?
I'd say a good five hours.
少说也有五个钟头吧
Huh. I expected the Rocky Mountains to be a little rockier than this.
我在想这里的落基山岩石比我想像中少太多了吧
I was thinking the same thing.
我也这么觉得
That John Denver is full of shit, man.
约翰·丹佛唱的都是狗屎
I'm only human, Harry.
我也只是凡人 哈利
Anybody can make a mistake.
人非圣贤 孰能无过嘛
Come on.
好了啦
Stop being a baby.
别像个小婴儿闹别扭啦
So we backtracked a tad.
不过就往回走一点点嘛
A tad?
一点点?
A tad, Lloyd?
一点点 劳埃德?
You drove almost a sixth of the way across the country in the wrong direction!
你穿越了整个国家的六分之一 都是往反方向开去!
Now we don't have enough money to get to Aspen.
现在我们的钱不够去亚斯本了!
we don't have enough money to get home! we don't have enough money to eat!
没钱回家! 没钱吃饭!
we don't have enough money to sleep!
没钱睡觉!
well, it's not gonna do us any good to sit here whining about it.
不过 我们光在这吵架 不是一点用也没有
we're in a hole.
我们陷入了一个困境
we're just gonna have to dig ourselves out.
我们就得要想办法靠自己 去度过啊
Okay. Right. You're right.
是啊 说的好 你说的真好
You're absolutely right, Lloyd.
你永远是对的 劳埃德
where you going?
你去哪啊?
Home. I'm walking home.
回家 我走路回家
Oh, well, pardon me, Mr.Perfect!
这样啊 随便你 完美先生!
I guess I forgot that you never, ever make a mistake.
我想我忘了你是一个不曾犯错的圣人!
Harry!
哈利!
Harry. wait up.
哈利 等等
Got room for one more if you still wanna go to Aspen.
去亚斯本吗 这儿还有个空位
where did you find that?
你去哪搞来这么个玩意儿?
Some kid back in town.
后镇的小鬼头弄到的
Traded the van for it, straight up.
我把你的大狗车拿去换
I can get 70 miles to the gallon on this hog.
这家伙光一加仑的汽油 就能跑70哩了
You know, Lloyd...
劳埃德 我一直觉得...
just when I think you couldn't possibly be any dumber...
你实在蠢得不能再蠢了...
you go and do something like this...
不过你刚刚的做法...
and totally redeem yourself!
证明我以前是冤枉你了!
Still wanna go to Aspen? Oh, yeah.
还去不去亚斯本? 废话
Okay. Let's go, buddy. Super!
来吧 我们走吧 哥们 出发!
Lloyd, no, west.Go west, Lloyd. Oh, yeah.
不是这边! 往西! 往西 劳埃德! 对哈
I got...I gotta stop and go to the bathroom.
我要......我要停下去方便
Just go, man.
就地解决 老弟
That sure is warm.
还挺温暖的
we're there.
咱们到了
Got a little nippy going through the pass, huh, Har?
这儿好像有点冻的受不了
lsn't this incredible?
是不是很不可思议吗?
what more could two single guys ask for? How about some food?
两个单身汉还能要求什么? 找点吃的怎样?
I swallowed a big June bug when we were driving.I'm not really hungry.
刚刚骑车时 我吞了一只金甲虫 现在饱了
Yeah, well, I'm starving.
不过我可快饿死了
Jeez, look at the butt on that.
老天 看看那屁股
Yeah.
是啊
He must work out.
他一定在健身
Hey. why don't we get busy and deliver the briefcase to Mary.
我们何不立即把手提箱送回给玛丽
If I know her as well as I think I do, she'll invite us in for tea and strumpets.
如果她与我想像的一样 她会请我们喝茶和嫖妓的
Good plan.where does she live?
好主意 她住哪?
I don't know.
天知道
what's her last name? I'll look it up.
那她姓什么? 我来查查
You know, I don't really recall.
这个......我实在记不太清楚了
It starts with an S.
开头是S
Swim, Swamie, Slippy...
斯魏敏......斯旺米......斯力皮......
Slappy, Slimin, Solmon, Simmon...
斯赖皮......斯利敏......斯敏......撒尔......
Swan, Swenson, Swanson?
斯旺......斯文森......斯文森?
Maybe it's on the briefcase. Look on... Yeah. It's right here.
手提箱上或许有写 是啊 就在这儿
Samsonite. I was way off.
新秀丽! 我记错了呀
I knew it started with an S, though.
最起码我还记得是S开头的
I'm not seeing it here, Lloyd.
劳埃德 这上面没有
She must be unlisted.
那一定是没登记
Great.
棒呆了
So, what are we supposed to do now?
那我们现在何去何从?
I can't feeI my fingers anymore , Lloyd.
我的手指没感觉了
They're numb.
冻僵了
Maybe you should wear these extra gloves.
或许你该像我一样戴上手套
My hands are starting to get sweaty.
我的手都开始冒汗了
Extra gloves?
富余的手套? 两双?
You've had this pair of extra gloves this whole time?
从前面到现在你一直都戴着这两双手套?
Yeah. we're in the Rockies.
废话 我们在落基山耶
I'm going to kill you.
我要宰了你
what?
什么?
I'm gonna kill you. I'm gonna kill you, Lloyd.
我要宰了你! 劳埃德 我非宰了你不可
-Calm down. -Right now. I'm gonna kill you.
冷静 我要把你剁成肉酱! 马上!
Harry, you got that crazy look in your eye.
哈利 你的两眼充血了
-I know what I'm gonna do. -what are you doing?
我很清楚自己在做什么 你想干嘛?
I'm gonna do something I should have done a long time ago.
我要做一件我很早以前就该做的事
Don't do anything foolish, Harry.
哈利 别做傻事
what? Foolish? This isn't foolish.
什么? 傻事? 这一点都不傻
I'm gonna toss this damn curse right into that damn pond.
我要把这个该死的罪魁祸首丢进那个该死的湖泊里
-You're an asshole.No! Harry! -I'm gonna do it.
你是个混蛋 不要啊 哈利! 我要丢掉它!
Stop...
停下......
Harry...
哈利
your hands are freezing.
你的手还真冰
Harry. Look.
哈利 看
Look. Look.
看那 快看
Okay, here's the plan.
好吧 我的计划是这样
we borrow a few bucks, just a small loan, from the briefcase...
我们从手提箱里借出一点点钱......
and we find some reasonable lodgings. Good plan.
然后找个像样的地方住 赞成
we'll keep track all the money we spend with IOU's.
然后我们将所开销的 每一毛每一分
we'll be meticulous to the last penny. whatever we borrow, we pay back.
都清清楚楚写 成借条 不管如何 我们都会还的
Absolute...we're good for it. Our word is our bond.
毫无疑问......我们有借有还 我们说话算话
This is the Hotel Danbury presidential suite, gentlemen.
这里是丹伯里饭店的总统套房 绅士们
Normally reserved for royalty, visiting dignitaries...
按惯例来讲只提供给皇室达官政要......
illustrious stars of stage and screen.
银幕 舞台上的超级明星
we have shortly coming the emperor and empress of Japan.
还有即将到来的日本天皇
And of course, Prince Charles and Di when they were together...
当然 在查尔斯王子和戴安娜王妃 还在一起的时候......
used to frequent the hotel constantly. we'll take it.
也都是本饭店的常客 我们要了
There you go.
给你
There you go. Thank you, sir.
给你 谢谢
Rain brought them to him. My mother was Sarah Carver.
一场雨将他们带至他身边 我的妈妈是莎拉·卡佛
Although at the time he wasn't sure he wanted to accept the gift.
虽然此刻 他仍不确定是否接受这份天赐的礼物
Ned, do you think he'll let us stay?
尼克 你想他会让我们留下吗?
No, this place is ugly anyway. You and me , we're family.
不会 我都不喜欢这个地方 你和我 我们永远是一家人
I promise never to take you away.
我保证永远都不离开你
And no one's ever gonna break us apart.
没有任何事能将我们分开
At pacific Bell, we believe that's pretty special.
在太平洋贝尔电话公司 我们坚持重要时刻从不缺席
Oh, boy. This is living, huh?
这才是生活 对吧?
Yeah. what's on next?
是啊 接下来要作啥?
I don't know. Let me look it up.
我哪知道 我来看看
Lloyd, you okay?
劳埃德 你还好吧?
Harry...
哈利...
it's Mary.
是玛丽
who? Mary. with the briefcase?
谁? 玛丽啊 手提箱的主人
Mary Swanson.
玛丽·斯文森
Swanson. "will host a newl...."
斯文森 "将举办......"
"Host annual." "Host...
举办......一......一年...... 举办
annual...
一年一度......
Annual. annual meeting of...
一年一度 一一年一度的会议......
It's a big one.
这个词很长
"International Preservationists Society tomorrow night."
国际保护协会 明晚
well, come on, Cinderella, we gotta get you ready for the ball.
来吧 灰姑娘 该是你去舞会的时候了
Thanks, Barn.
谢了 车夫
There you go. Thank you, sir.
这是给你的 谢谢你 先生
You're right.
你是对的
Okay, okay, okay.
好了 好了 好了
Cripes. Yes, yes, yes.
烦死了 胜利 胜利 胜利
Time out.
暂停
Okay, time out.whatever.
好吧 时间到了 随便你
Excuse me, gentlemen. This is a $500-a-plate dinner. Good night.
抱歉 这里可是一道菜500以上的贵族圣区 再见
Oh, 500 . Oh, okay. All right, no problem.
500啊 好 没问题
Here, put us down for...Put us down for four.
这里 两张......四张......
In case we want seconds.
免得待会我们还要再给一次
Jesus Christ.
我的天啊
It's them.
是他们
Them who? Them. The guys who whacked Mental.
他们? 谁啊? 杀了曼特尔的那两个家伙
Can't you just feel it, Harry?
你能感觉到吗 哈利?
This is our big chance, man.
这次可是我们的良机了 伙伴
All we gotta do is show a little class, a little sophistication...
我们只需稍稍现一下我们的崇高地位和良好教养......
and we're in like a dirty shirt. No problem.
而且我们一点也不嫌贫爱富 没问题
we can be classy and sophis...Look at the funbags on that hosehound.
我们可是温文高贵的绅士 看那个丑女和她那对大奶子
I'd like to eat her liver...
我真想把她的肝脏和蚕豆吃了......
with some farver beans and a nice bottle of Chianti.
再配上一杯吉安地酒
Come on. Let's go get bowls of loudmouth soup.
走吧 咱们去找点开胃酒来喝
Yeah.
好啊
Hey, bartender, two martinis, please. Yes, sir.Right away.
酒保 来两杯马丁尼  好的 马上来
Ladies and gentlemen, your attention, please.
女士先生们 能大家听我说
The Aspen Preservation Society is the world's foremost defender...
这个亚斯本保护协会是保护世界上...
of 23 endangered species.
23种濒临绝种的物种的先驱
And it is with tremendous honor that we're able to bring Mr.Swanson forward...
现在 我们很荣幸地邀请到 斯文森先生......
to introduce us to the 24th, everybody.Karl.
来为我们介绍第24种 各位来宾 卡尔
Thank you.
谢谢你
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士们先生们......
I give you the lcelandic Snow Owl.
让我正式向你们介绍 来自冰岛的雪猫头鹰
These magnificent specimens...
这些华贵的动物是......
constitute one-seventh of the snow owl population left on the planet.
地球上仅存的雪猫头鹰中的七分之一
And God willing...
如果能靠......
with your help and that of the Society's...
在座各位来宾的帮助以及协会的努力下......
these wonderful creatures will flourish once more.
这些华丽的生物将会再次 繁衍兴盛起来
Thank you again and enjoy your evening.
再次感谢你们 请尽情享受今晚的时光
Could I have some pistachios, please?
能给我些开心果吗?
And another one of those.
还有这个也再来一杯
Lloyd, what are you doing? would you calm down? I've never seen you so nervous.
你在干嘛啦? 镇静些 我从没看你这么紧张过
Keep an eye on them, Shay.
盯着他们 雪伊
Keep a close eye.
紧紧盯牢
I'm ready for commitment, Harry.
哈利 我准备好要对她许诺了
First time I set eyes on Mary Swanson...
我第一眼见到玛丽·斯文森时......
I just got that old-fashioned romantic feeling...
我就有种老式的浪漫感觉......
where I'd do anything to bone her.
我能做任何事来取悦她
That's a special feeling, Lloyd.Yeah. Oh, yeah?
那真是很特别的感觉 劳埃德 是的
Oh, my. There she is.
老天 她在那
wow, you weren't kidding, Lloyd.
原来你不是盖的耶 劳埃德
She's an angel.
她真是个天使
what are you waiting for? Get over there and talk to her.
你还呆在这里干嘛? 过去和她说话啊
She's gonna think I'm a psycho when she finds out how far I came just to see her.
她一定会以为我是神经病大老远跑来这儿看她
You know what you have. Her briefcase.
你知道你的优势是什么吗? 你有她的手提箱
She's gonna be thrilled to see you.
她见到你会很感动的
wait, I have an idea.
等等 我有主意了
why don't you go over and introduce yourself...
何不你过去向她自我介绍......
and that way you can build me up so I won't have to brag about myself later.
然后顺便吹捧一下我 这样等会儿我就不用再自吹自擂了
Tell her I'm rich and I'm good-looking and I have a rapist wit.
跟她说我很有钱而且长得又帅 还有过人的才智幽默
No.I don't...No.I don't think I could.
不 我不认为我能
No, I'm not...That's not... Come on, please.Oh, Har, please.
不 我不会..... 拜托 求你了 哈利
Please. Okay, okay, okay, stop.
求你 求你 求你 好 好 停下
what are you gonna do?
那你现在呢?
I'm gonna hang by the bar...
我去吧台那儿晃晃......
put out the vibe.
我的幸福靠你了
Okay.
没问题
Nice set of hooters you got there.
你的胸部真平
I beg your pardon. The owls. They're beautiful.
你说什么 我是说那些猫头鹰 它们很美
Yeah.
是啊
Are you a bird lover?
你是鸟类爱好者吗?
Me? Oh, no. well, I used to have a parakeet...
我? 不是的 我以前是有养过鹦鹉......
but now my main area of expertise is canines.
但我现在专门热衷的是犬科动物
Dogs, to the layperson.
小狗 一般人的说法
Thanks.
多谢解释
I love dogs too.
我也喜欢小狗
So how are you involved with them? Oh, I...You know, I've trained them.
那你怎么地热衷法? 就是......训练它们
You know, bathed them, clipped them. I've even bred them.
帮它们洗澡和修剪毛发 我甚至还帮他们做媒
Oh, really? Any unusual breeding?
真的? 有发生什么有趣事吗?
No, mostly just doggie style.
没有 不过就很普通的那种
One time, we successfully mated a bulldog with a Shih Tzu.
有一次 我们很顺利地帮一只牛头犬和一只狮子狗 配对成功
Really? That's weird.
真的假的? 太不可思议了
Yeah, we called it a bullshit.
是啊 我们叫它做狗屎
Oh, I'm...Anyway, the reaI reason I came over here was to...
对了 我来这里的真正原因是......
I gotta introduce you to a buddy of mine .
我想向你介绍我一位朋友
Oh, Mary, I don't believe I've met your friend.
我还没见过你朋友呢 玛丽
Oh, well, actually, we haven't been properly introduced.
实际上我们还尚未 正式地自我介绍
My name is Mary Swanson.
我叫做玛丽·斯文森
Hi, Harry Dunne. Hi, nice to meet you.
哈利·邓恩 很高兴认识你
This is my stepmother, Helen.
这位是我的继母 海伦
Hi, Harry Dunne. Pleasure to meet you both.
我是哈利·邓恩 真的很荣幸认识你们俩
well, I saw you come in. I was hoping I'd get a chance to meet you.
我有看见你走进来就一直希望能有机会认识你
-You were? Really. -Yes.
你说真的? 当然
That tuxedo, it's fabulous.
那燕尾服实在太棒了
Really, I love a man with a sense of humor.
真的 我喜欢幽默风趣的男人
Really. And so does Mary. It's hysterical.
玛丽也是 这真是太好笑了
-Really? -Oh, yes.
你是吗? 对
Anyway, yeah, about my friend... what are you doing tomorrow?
不管怎样 关于我朋友......  你明天有空吗?
Mary is looking for someone to hit the slopes with.
我知道玛丽一直想找人同去滑雪
She what? Huh?
她......什么?
Helen, you're embarrassing me.
海伦 你让我为难了
Yeah, well, you are.
你想去的 不是吗?
After all, the snow's gonna be gone in a couple of weeks...
毕竟再过几星期 雪季就要结束了......
and this may be your last chance. She never gets a chance to get out.
而这可能是你最后玩雪的机会 她从来都不会找机会出门逛逛
well, what do you say, Mr.Dunne? Are you available?
你的决定呢 邓恩先生? 有空吗?
I don't know. My friend... Forget about your friend for one day.
我不确定 我朋友...... 就一天 忘了你朋友吧
I think you kids will have a wonderful time. what do you say?
我想你们俩会有个愉快的时光的 怎么样?
well, you know, I don't know, you know, the thing, part...Sure, what time?
不过 我不晓得 这件事...... 当然! 什么时候?
How come you didn't bring her over?
你怎能没把她带过来?
Relax, you're golden. I got you a date with her tomorrow.
别紧张......你走运了 我帮你约到她了 明天
Oh, you are...what? I can't...This...I love you, man.
什么......我不敢相......我爱死你了 兄弟
Okay, okay, you're kissing me.
行了 行了 你在亲我
You're kissing me, Lloyd... I love you.
你在亲我的头 劳埃德......我爱你
Oh, God.
我的天呐
This calls for a little of the bubbly.
来开瓶香槟庆祝庆祝吧
You're gonna be my best man. Good.
你会是我的伴郎的 那真荣幸啊
I promise. Thank you.
我保证 还真谢谢你
You have just earned yourself a seat at the head table, pal.
你替你自己赢得了VIP 头等座位 伙计
And we already got the tuxes.
而且我们已经有燕尾服了
Boy, this party really died.
看来这个晚会似乎完了
Hey, maybe it was a coincidence.
或许那只是巧合
"Hey, maybe it was a coincidence."
"或许那只是巧合"
It was a message, Shay, pure and simple.
是个警讯  显而易见的
I mean, we killed their bird. Now they killed one of ours.
我们杀了他们的鸟 现在换他们杀了我们的
How could anybody whack a bird with a cork?
怎么可能有人单单用一只软木塞 就能宰了一只鸟
These guys aren't just anybody.
这俩家伙不是寻常老百姓
They're good.
他们可是高手
Mary Christmas.
玛丽·克里斯穆斯
Mrs. Mary Christmas.
玛丽·克里斯穆斯太太
Kind of catchy, huh, Har?
十分好记 对吧 哈利?
Yeah, yeah, that sounds nice, Lloyd...
对 对 对 听起来很顺耳 劳埃德......
but, don't you think you might be jumping the gun a little bit?
不过 劳埃德 你不觉得 你现在高兴的太早了吗?
I mean, you know.who knows?
我是说 谁知道呢
Maybe once you get to know her, you'll find out that she's not your type.
可能将来哪天 你深层认识她后 你会发现她根本不是你要的那型
Don't you ever say that again.
刚刚那句话给我收回去
She is the love of my life!
她就是我此生的挚爱!
The blood in my veins.
已经融入我的血脉中
we belong together!
我们是彼此相属的!
Till the mountains fall into the sea, till the heavens collide...
无论海枯石烂 直到天荒地老......
or until I get sick of her and need to move on.You hear me?
直到有一天慢慢老去 你听懂了没?
Okay, okay, okay. Lloyd, just calm down.
懂 懂 懂 淡定 淡定
Just calm down.
淡定
Okay.
淡定了
Now.
现在
Let me get this straight.
咱们再重新确认一次
Lobby bar in the lobby.
大厅里的大堂酒吧
Yeah, that's what she said. She'll meet you there at 10:00 sharp.
不错 那是她说的 十点整她会在那里等你
-Okay. -Okay.
好的  好的
where you going in that getup?
你穿这身行头去哪啊?
I just thought when, you know, you'd be off making your love connection...
我只是想 既然你去甜甜蜜蜜地约会了......
I'd be out, trying my luck on the slopes.
那我也要出去转转溜溜 碰碰运气
You mean you're gonna go out in public dressed in tights?
你是说你要穿这身紧身裤到公共场所去?
No, these aren't tights, Lloyd.
不 这不是紧身裤 劳埃德
These are fashionable Eurotrash ski trousers.
这可是欧洲最流行的滑雪装
Pretty revealing.
相当暴露
Really?
真的吗?
Yeah, but it's just a tiny lump. No one will notice.
有点吧 不过就那么一小坨不会有人注意到的
You're right. I can't go out dressed like this.
你说的对 我不能穿这样出去见人
Hey! Coming!
我来了
Nice going, buddy.
老兄 身手不错
Ma'am.
女士
Beautiful outfit, sir.
先生 您的服装真不错
There you go.
给你
How you doing?
早安
You're a little early. we don't open for about 45 minutes.
你来的有点早 我们45分钟后才营业
I'm meeting someone here.
我和人约在这里
Mind if I wait at the bar?
介意我在吧台等吗?
No, come on in.
不会 进来吧
It's a beautiful day, huh, Harry?
今天天气真好 对吧 哈利?
Yes, yes, I've had a wonderful time so far. Thank you.
是啊 这是我人生中最美好的一天 谢谢你
God, it feels so good to get up here.
老天 上来这儿感觉真不错
I haven't been outside that much in the last couple of weeks.
周末时我不常出来
Oh, yeah? why not?
是吗 为什么不呢?
There's been some family problems...
呃...就是些家庭问题...
but I don't wanna bore you with those.
现在说这个不太好
Thanks.
谢了
Oh, look. Frost.
你瞧 有霜
Harry?
哈利?
Are you okay? Oh, yeah. I just...I do this all the time.
你没事吧? 没事 我常常这么玩地
Hi there.
隔壁的
Say, kids.
小鬼头 快跟我说
You wouldn't happen to have a cup of warm water, would you?
你们有没有 热水
Excuse me.
借问一下
ls it 10 a.m.yet?
上午10点过了没?
It's 1.
下午1点了
That's what I have too.
我的表也是
I thought maybe it was fast.
我还以为走快了
She's running late, huh?
她真慢 是吧?
Just a couple hours.
不过就几小时
You know girls.
女孩子嘛
when they're excited about something...
当她们很注重某人时......
everything has to be perfect.
全身上下打扮都会力求完美
This one's on me.
这瓶我请的
Yippee.
好哦
Chablis, please.
一杯夏布利酒 谢谢
Hello.
哈罗
Bad day, huh?
今天超衰 对吧?
Me too.
我也是
Of course, everything's been bad since I broke up with my boyfriend.
自从我和男友分手后所有的一切都慢慢变糟了
My God.
我的天哪
You poor guy. Does it hurt?
你这个可怜人 疼吗?
Oh, no. I'm fine. I saved a seat for you.
我没事 还替你留了个位子
Oh, no. Listen, this is silly.
不 别管那些了
Let me help you. No, no, no.
让我来帮你吧 不 不 不
It will only hurt for a moment, like a Band-Aid.
就痛一下下 像撕胶带一样
Come on, ready? No, no, no.
准备好 不 不 不!
No. Come on. Go.
不  一 二 三 拔
Let go! Help! Help!
放手! 救命! 救命!
Come on. Come on, come on.
来吧 来吧 来吧
what am...?
这是......?
I said to myself, "Run, Beth.Run for your life before this man kills you both."
我对自己说 "快跑 在那人杀了你们俩之前快跑"
Then do you know what the klutz did?
然后你知道那蠢蛋说什么吗?
No, and I don't care.
不知道 我也不在乎
I'm gonna tell you. He came home one night dead drunk...
我再继续告诉你 有一晚 他喝个烂醉回来...
and decided he wanted to fix the sink. I couldn't believe him.
然后说他要修理水槽
Anyway, enough about me. Let's talk about you. How come you're here?
他的话真是不能信 好了 谈谈你吧 你怎么会来到这里?
Bartender. How come?
酒保 什么事
You wouldn't happen to know a Mary Swanson, would you?
你不会刚好认识一个叫 玛丽·斯文森的吧?
Mary Swanson?
玛丽·斯文森?
Yeah, she comes in here all the time.
认识啊 她常常都来这里
what's that supposed to mean? She has dinner.
什么意思? 她来这里吃饭
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Do you know where she lives?
那你知道她住哪吗?
Yeah, her family has the big place up on Alpine Drive.
知道啊 她们家是阿尔卑斯大道上的大户人家
Alpine Drive?
阿尔卑斯大道?
Big place?
大户人家?
No way.
不是吧
That's great.
真是好极了
we landed on the moon!
我们登陆月球了!
I've gotta tell you, today was just what I needed.
我想说我今天过得很愉快
Thanks a lot, Harry.
真的很谢谢你 哈利
Oh, it was...
这个......那个......
It was my pleasure, Mary.
玛丽 这是我的荣幸
So you'll pick me up tonight at 7:45?
那你今晚7点45来接我?
well, no. I got a few things to take care of first.
不 我还有些事情要处理一下
But why don't we make it quarter to 8?
所以我们为何不改在 八点差一刻的时候?
Stop it.
得了吧你
Okay, 7:45.
7点45 没问题
Bye.
再见
It doesn't make any sense, Lloyd. She told me 10:00 sharp.
劳埃德 这没道理啊 她告诉我的就是十点整
Are you sure you went to the right bar?
你确定你没找错地方?
Oh, yeah.Yeah.
当然 再正确不过了
I'm pretty sure.
我十分肯定.
Lobby bar, right in the lobby.
大堂酒吧...... 就在大厅里......
Maybe she just had a change of heart.
或许只是她改变心意了
Oh, that pisses me off. That pisses me right off.
那十分惹人厌的! 我超级讨厌!
I hate when women do that, you know?
我恨死女人这样三心两意
She wanted to see you again. She told me that.
她是想再见到你的 她是这样告诉我
And now, no? Now...wait a minute.wait.
现在呢? 现在...... 等一下! 等等!
She must have meant 10:00 at night.
她说的肯定是晚上的十点
Do you think?
你觉得呢?
why would she have you meet her at a bar at 10 in the morning?
她在早上十点到酒吧去干嘛?
I just figured she was a raging alcoholic.
我只是想她也许是 嗜酒成性罢了
Oh, that's the...
那实在太...
And all this time I've been going through such pain and personal anguish.
在今天这段时间里我一直在水深火热中煎熬
Such hell, for nothing.
宛如地狱! 结果呢? 根本没事!
Oh, God, that's funny. Oh, that's good stuff.
天啊! 真是太好笑了 这笑话实在是不错!
Oh, boy. well, looks like you got your night planned...
这样 看来你似乎要去 准备你晚上的约会......
so I'm gonna head out, catch a flick.
那我也要出门去看场电影了
Okay.
请吧
Ten in the morning.
上午十点
Hey, Harry, old buddy, old pal.
哈利 我的老朋友 死搭档
Yeah?
有何贵干?
will you join me in a good-luck toast before you head out?
在你出门前 咱们来干一杯吧
Sure. whatever you think will help your chances.
再好不过 你确定这有助你的好运就行了
Yes, sirree.
是的 非常
You know why I like you, Harry?
你知道我为何喜欢你吗 哈利?
Because you're a regular guy.
因为你十分忠厚老实
Yep.
对
That's why I want you to stay regular.
是啊 这就是我希望你继续忠厚老实的原因
One half-teaspoon for fast, effective relief.
二分之一小匙 即用即效!
To my friend, Harry...
敬我的朋友 哈利!
the matchmaker.
最佳媒人!
Get out of here.I'm...I've...
别这样说 我只不过是...
Hi, the door's open.Come on upstairs.
门打开着 请上来吧
Hi.Make yourself at home. I'm almost ready. One minute?
随一点 我快要好了 等我一分钟
Okay. Sounds good. Okay.
好的 你动作很快嘛 是的
Harry? Are you in there?
哈利 你在里面吗?
Be right out.
马上就好
I hope you're not using the toilet. It's broken.
我希望你还没使用马桶 它坏了
Huh?
什么
The toilet doesn't flush.
马桶不能冲水了
No, I was just shaving.
没有 我只是刮一下胡子
Shaving?
刮胡子?
Yeah, I was running a little late. I thought this would save some time.
是的 我出门时有点晚了想省点时间
Okay.
好吧
I'll be in the kitchen whenever you're ready.
我在厨房等你弄好
Oh, jeez.
我的妈呀
Tomorrow on A Current Affair...
今天社会追缉令......
inside the home of the Menendez brothers, attorney.
现场在梅能德斯兄弟律师事务所里
And next, we'll be back in a minute...
休息片刻稍后回来......
with the heartbreaking story of the bIind Rhode IsIand boy...
我们将讲述一个令人悲痛的故事 一个失明的罗德岛小男孩......
who was duped into buying a dead parakeet.
被人欺骗买到一只死鹦鹉
I just thought he was real quiet.
我以为它只是太过安静了
who are these sick people?
怎么会有这些变态?
Yes?
有事吗?
Remember me?
还记得我吗?
Not really.
不是很清楚
Providence. Providence.
普罗维顿斯
I drove you to the airport last week.
我载你去机场的 上星期
Oh, my God.
我的天啊!
Lloyd, right?
劳埃德 对吧?
You remembered my name.
你没忘记我的名字
what are you doing in Aspen?
你来亚斯本有什么事吗?
I brought you your briefcase.
来把手提箱送还给你
You left it at the airport, you big goof.
你忘记在机场里的 你这个小迷糊蛋
You have my briefcase? Yeah.
你捡了我的手提箱? 是啊
Hey, I have it at my hotel room.
我把它放在我饭店的房间里了
wanna jump on the bike with me? we can go get it.Unless....
你要跟我骑车去拿吗? 这就去 除非......
Unless you're busy. I'll...
除非你现在有事 那我就......
Oh, no.No. No...No, I don't wanna...
不 不 不 我并不想......
You just wait right here, okay? Okay.
你就在这里等我一下 好吗 好的
Come on, flush, you bastard.
快动啊! 冲水啊! 你这个烂马桶!
Harry, what are you doing in there?
哈利 你在里边做什么?
Uh...Uh...I'm just...I'm cleaning my teeth.
我 我 我在刷牙!
Harry?
哈利?
I'm gargling.
现在在漱口
Just give me a minute, Mary. I'll be right with you.
再等我一下下 玛丽 我马上就好
Harry, I'm sorry, but something important has come up and I've got to run out.
哈利 抱歉 我临时有很重要的事现在必须出去
It's sort of an emergency. I'll explain later.
是紧急情况 我回来再解释
But, Mary... I'm sorry, Harry.
玛丽 等...  很抱歉 哈利
I've really got to go. I promise we'll do this again sometime.
我真的得走了我保证下次会补偿你的
Race you to the top.
看谁先跑上去
Come here.
来吧
Yeah!
到达!
I won.
我赢了
Look familiar?
很眼熟吧?
I don't believe it.You really have it. Of course I have it.
真不敢相信你真带来了! 当然 我捡到了嘛
when Lloyd Christmas drives a woman to the airport...
当劳埃德·克里斯穆斯开车送一位女士去机场时......
he makes sure she gets her luggage. That's my whole philosophy.
他必须确认她是否有带上全部的行李 这就是我的行事原则
This is incredible.
难以置信
You mean to say you drove 2000 miles just for me?
你是说你横跨两千里只为了我?
I didn't really have a lot to do, you know...
这没什么大不了的......
and I know how frustrating it can be to lose a bag.
我知道那种遗失东西的沮丧挫折感
That is so sweet, Lloyd.
劳埃德 你真贴心
Look, Mary.
玛丽
I know this may seem a little sudden but I've given it a lot of thought.
这对你或许十分突然但是我已经深思熟虑了许久
You're the woman I've been waiting for my whole life...
你就是我此生在等待的唯一女人......
and I'm not ashamed to admit it. Please...
我一点也不耻于承认这个 请......
let me finish.
让我先说完
I'm crazy about you.
我为你几尽疯狂了
I've never felt this way about anybody.
我从未对别人有过这样的感觉
Listen to me. I feel like a schoolboy again.
看看我......就像学生时代的毛头小子
A schoolboy who desperately wants to make sweet, sweet love to you.
情窦初开的小毛头 不顾一切地只为追求他的爱情
I thought I heard you talking to someone.
你刚刚是不是在和谁说话?
Mary.
玛丽
I desperately wanna make love to a schoolboy.
我十分想和男学童做爱
Maybe I should be going. No, no.
我要走了! 不! 不
No, I've...
不 这不是......
That's not what I meant.
这不是我想说的
what I meant was...
我想说的是......
I like you, Mary.
玛丽 我喜欢你
I like you a lot...
我非常喜欢你......
and I wanna ask you a question, straight out, flat out...
我想问你很直接的问题......
and I want you to give me the honest answer.
我需要你给我诚实的回答
what do you think the chances are of a guy like you and a girl like me...
你觉得像这种情况 你这样的男人和我这样的女孩......
ending up together?
在一起的机率有多少?
well, Lloyd, that's difficult to say. we really don't...
这个......很难说 劳埃德 我们根本尚未......
Hit me with it. Just give it to me straight.
回答我! 就坦白的告诉我!
I came a long way just to see you, Mary. Just...
我长途跋涉来此 就只为了见你 而你......
The least you can do is level with me.
你只需告诉我一个答案
what are my chances?
我的机会有多少?
Not good.
不太大
You mean "not good" like one out of a hundred?
你说的不太大 百分之一有吗?
I'd say...more like one out of a million.
我指的是百万分之一
So you're telling me there's a chance.
你是说我还有这百万分之一的一丝机会
Yeah!
好极了!
I read you.
我懂你意思了
we have plenty of towels. Thanks.
我们的毛巾够了 谢谢
Nicholas. what are you doing here?
尼古拉斯 你在这里干嘛?
I've been looking for you, Mary. I have some news about your husband.
我一直在找你 玛丽 我有了关于你丈夫的消息
Husband?
丈夫?
wait a minute.
暂停一下
what was all that one-in-a-million talk?
刚刚那百万分之一之说又怎讲?
Aren't you gonna invite me in?
你们不邀请我进去吗?
Hey, Harry.You never called.
哈利 你怎没打电话来?
what are you doing here?
你在这儿做什么?
Excuse me, gunman.
请问一下 这位拿枪的
who are you? Oh, don't play dumb with me, asshole.
你是谁啊? 别跟我装傻 你这个白痴
I'm the rightful owner of that briefcase that you've been carrying around.
我就是那个被你拿着到处转的手提箱的主人
Oh, well, then.
原来如此
Nicholas, my family trusted you.
尼古拉斯 我家人都很信任你的
Shut up.
闭嘴
Listen, Mr.Samsonite, about the briefcase.
新秀丽先生 关于那个手提箱
My friend Harry and I have every intention of fully reimbursing you.
我朋友哈利和我正打算 用尽各种方法来好好补偿你一番
what are you talking about?
你说什么?
You open it up. Open it up.
你来打开它 快开
Go ahead. Open it up.
去开啊 快去
Do what he says.
照他的话去做
Hurry.
快点
what is this? what is this? where's all the money?
这些是什么鬼东西? 什么鬼东西啊? 里面的钱呢?
That's as good as money, sir.
那和钱一样有效的 先生
Those are lOU's.
那些是借据
Go ahead and add it up. Every cent's accounted for.
把它们全部加起来 一毛都没有少的
Look.
瞧
See this? That's a car.
看见这张没? 是买一辆车用的
Two hundred and seventy-five thou. Might wanna hang on to that one.
27万5千 实在超级想要那辆
You're a dead man. You're a dead man!
你死定了 你死定了!
Lloyd!
劳埃德
I'm home.
我回来了
Look, we've gotta have a serious talk.
听着 我们应该好好地谈一谈
I got a confession to make.
我有点事情要对你据实以告
Oh, good.You found her. I'll leave you two alone.
太好了 你终于见到她了 我就不妨碍二位了
No, stay.
不用走 留下
Yes, I'd like a one-way ticket to Amsterdam...
是的 我要一张去阿姆斯特丹的单程票......
departing as soon as possible, please.
越快越好
Okay, how do you guys know each other?
你们两家伙怎么认识的?
we used to be best friends. Yeah, until he turned into a backstabber.
我们曾经是最好的朋友 是啊 直到他开始暗箭伤人
Me a backstabber? You got a lot of nerve.
我暗箭伤人? 这种话你也好意思说
-You knew I was crazy about her. Yeah.
你知道我多为她疯狂 知道
You knew I was crazy about Fraida Felcher...
你还不是知道我十分着迷 弗洛伊德·佛吉尔......
and that didn't stop you, did it?
而你还不照样挖墙角 对吧?
what do you mean?
你什么意思?
"what do you mean?" Don't deny it, Lloyd.
"你什么意思? " 别装傻 劳埃德
Fraida told me the whole sleazy story, Mr.French Tickler.
弗洛伊德告诉我 整个事情的真相了 保险套男
Okay, what time does it...? what time does that leave?
好的 什么时候......何时能离开?
Thank you. Hey, wait a second.
谢谢你 再等一下
Can I have a vegetarian meal?
能替我准备素食餐吗?
we both learned something about each other today, didn't we?
我想我们今天从对方身上都学到了点东西 对吗?
Yeah, you said it, pal.
是的 你说的对 伙计
we're not as good friends as we thought. Yeah, guess not.
或许我们不像想像中地那般要好 我也这么认为
I mean, if one beautiful girl can rip us apart like this...
我是说 如果一个美女就可以让我们像这样分道扬镳......
then our friendship isn't worth a damn. we should call quits right now.
我们的友谊 根本什么也不是 也许我们现在就划清一切
You just tell me where to sign, bud. Right on my ass, after you kiss it.
那你告诉我画在哪  用你的嘴巴在我的屁股上画
Kiss it? You kiss mine. Both cheeks, both lips, right here.
亲你的? 你亲我的还差不多耶! 两边屁股一边一次 现在!
Come on, come on.Put it right... Shut up.
放下 闭嘴!
Now, which one of you losers wants to get it first?
现在 哪个死人头要先走一步?
Over here.
在场的这些
I was the one that got you into this whole mess.
我是让你陷入这场混乱的元凶
Come on, shoot me.
来吧 杀了我吧
No, wait.
不! 等等!
wait, no, no. Do me first.
等等! 不要 不要 先杀我
I stole your girl. I deserve it. No, you don't.
我抢了你的女孩 这是我应得的报应 不 你没有
Yes, I do. No, you don't. No.
是我 我的确抢了 没 你没抢 没有
Yes, I do. Yesterday was one of the greatest days of my life.
要的 我当然抢了 昨天是我生命中最美好的一天
Mary and I went skiing, we made a snowman, she touched my leg.
玛丽和我一起滑雪 堆雪人 她还摸了我的大腿
Okay, kill him.
如你所愿 宰了他
Oh, no.
不!
You killed my best friend, you bastard!
你杀了我最好的朋友 你这个杂种!
well, if it's any consolation, you're about to be reunited.
放心 用不着太难过你们马上又会在一起了
Harry.
哈利
You're alive!
你还活着!
And you're a horrible shot.
不过你的枪法还真是烂的恐怖
Lucky me. Police officers! Nobody move!
我很幸运 警察! 任何人不许动!
Everybody freeze! All right, get those hands up!
谁都不准动! 把手举起来!
Not you, dummy.
不是说你 笨蛋
Get the gun. Look out, look out.
先拿枪 小心 小心
Special Officer Beth Jordan, FBI.
特别探员贝丝·乔登 FBI
Hey.who? But...Huh?
什么? 可是......
Mr.Dunne, thank you very much. we couldn't have done it without you.
邓恩先生 非常感激你的协助 没有你我们完成不了这个任务
we've been following you guys all the way from Providence.
我们一直跟踪你们俩 从普罗维顿斯开始
what's going on, Harry?
接下来还会有什么 哈利?
Your name is Harry, isn't it?
你的名字是哈利 没错吧?
Yeah, she grabbed me down in the lobby, explained what was up...
没错 她在大厅里抓住我 解释发生了什么事......
and then they slapped this bulletproof vest on me and gave me a gun.
接着他们就给我这件防弹衣还有一把枪
But what if he shot you in the face?
但万一他直接朝你的脸开枪呢?
what if he shot me in the face?
万一他直接朝我的脸开枪呢?
That's a risk we were willing to take.
这是我们愿意承担的风险
How come I didn't get a gun?
为何我就没枪拿?
Did you get a gun?
你有吗?
You were right, Lloyd.
你说得对 劳埃德
She was definitely worth the trip.
光她就值了这趟旅途
Yeah.
废话
She's something, ain't she, Har?
她可是珍品 对吧?
I'm glad we were able to help her out.
我很高兴我们能帮助到她
Bobby. Easy, easy.
亲爱的! 轻点 轻点
You're okay. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm okay, I'm just a little sore.
你没事吧 我没事 只是还有点痛
Oh, sweetie. Oh, baby, I missed your loving.
对不起 甜心 宝贝 我好想你
There's someone I want to introduce you to.
亲爱的 我想向你介绍个很棒的人
He's kindest, gentlest man I've ever met. will you meet him?
他是我见过最体贴的绅士 你会见他吗
Sure. Okay.
当然 来吧
He's got a gun!
他手上有枪!
Die! Lloyd, Lloyd.
死定了! 劳埃德 劳埃德
I said, this is my husband, Bobby.
我说 这位就是我的丈夫 鲍比
Oh. Hi, Bobby. Hi.
你好 鲍比   你好
I'm so happy for you.
我真替你感到高兴
Thank you.Thank you both very much.
谢谢 真的是十分感激你们二位
I owe you both a debt of gratitude.
我欠你们一个大人情
Thank you.
谢谢
I can't believe this, Lloyd.
太离谱了 劳埃德
First, Mary dumps us, then the cops take our nest egg...
先是玛丽抛弃了我们 接着条子拿走我们的养老金......
and then our hog breaks down.
然后是车子报销了
Yeah.when are we ever gonna catch a break?
是啊 好运何时才会降临在我们身上?
Hi, y'all.
大家好
Hey, guys.
小伙子们
we're going on a national bikini tour, and we're looking for two oil boys...
伙计 我们正要参加一场国际比基尼巡回比赛而我们在找两个......
who can grease us up before each competition.
愿意在赛前为我们抹乳液的男孩
You are in luck.
你们真是太幸运了
There's a town about three miles that way. I'm sure you'll find a couple guys there.
前面三里路就有小镇 你们能在那里找到人的
Okay, thanks. Bye.
是吗 多谢 再见
Do you realize what you've done?
你真的知道你干了什么好事吗?
Hey, wait! Lloyd!
等等 劳埃德!
Lloyd!
劳埃德!
You'll have to excuse my friend. He's a little slow.
请原谅我的朋友 他实在有点钝钝呆呆的
The town is back that way.
那个小镇是在反方向
Two lucky guys are gonna be driving around...
有两个幸运的家伙......
with those girls for the next couple of months.
将可以围在那些美女身边共渡好几个月
Yeah.
是啊
Don't worry, we'll catch our break too.
别担心 我们也会有我们的好运的
Just gotta keep our eyes open.
只要我们时刻准备好
Yep.
对啊
You're it.
你是猪
You're it. You're it. Quitsies.
你才是猪 你是猪 句号
You're it. Anti-quitsies, double stamp. You're it.Anti-quitsies, triple stamp.
你是猪 句号相反 踩踩 你是猪 句号相反 踩踩踩
No erasies. You can't triple stamp.
禁止消除无限有效 你不能踩三次.
Can't triple stamp a double stamp. You can.
如果你说踩两次当然可以 不行这样
You can't triple stamp. Lloyd, you can't triple a double stamp.
我踩过两次 劳埃德 你就不能再踩下去了
You can't triple stamp. That's the rule. You can't triple.
你不能踩第三次 这是游戏规则 就是不能踩
You can't triple stamp a double stamp, Lloyd. Lloyd! Lloyd!
你不能踩三次啦 劳埃德 劳埃德 劳埃德!